<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Future Has Arrived</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Future Has Arrived</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Correction in the Making?</title>
      <link>/2018/11/02/a-correction-in-the-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/02/a-correction-in-the-making/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week I came across this Datastream chart of the spread between the Russell 1000 Growth and Value Indices since 1979. With last month’s tech sector melt down front of mind – it paints an intriguing picture – of growth pitching down from a similar level to where it was at the start of the tech wreck in 2001.
Does the chart imply that growth investors are way out in front of value investors (as measured by the Russell indices), but stand on the precipice of a potentially violent correction?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dumb is Your Data?</title>
      <link>/2018/08/13/how-dumb-is-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/13/how-dumb-is-your-data/</guid>
      <description>Recently there seems to be an escalation of hype around AI. One recent article by Nan Li entitled, The New Intelligence starts like this
 Modern AI and the fundamental undoing of the scientific method The days of traditional, human-driven problem solving — developing a hypothesis, uncovering principles, and testing that hypothesis through deduction, logic, and experimentation — may be coming to an end. A confluence of factors (large data sets, step-change infrastructure, algorithms, and computational resources) are moving us toward an entirely new type of discovery, one that sits far beyond the constraints of human-like logic or decision-making: driven solely by AI, rooted in radical empiricism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Like Abilities - In 30 Lines of Code</title>
      <link>/2018/08/10/human-like-abilities-in-30-lines-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/10/human-like-abilities-in-30-lines-of-code/</guid>
      <description>Recent advances in deep learning have invigorated interest in data driven AI. Previous solutions to problems involving hand crafted features have been replaced by algorithms which take care of these steps for us – promoting data driven methods to a new level of radical empiricism. And the results can be pretty amazing. In part one of this series we’ll build a deep learning neural network for image classification in 30 lines of python code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction To The Boostrap For Quantitative Stock Selection</title>
      <link>/2018/05/30/an-introduction-to-the-boostrap-for-quantitative-stock-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/30/an-introduction-to-the-boostrap-for-quantitative-stock-selection/</guid>
      <description>Quantifying uncertainty is a fundamental and challenging task in financial modelling. In this post we’ll look at the bootstrap technique and how it can be applied to quantitative models. More generally, the bootstrap lies at the heart of a statistical technique called Bootstap Aggregation (bagging for short), which is the basis for machine learning algorithms such as random forest.
The Bootstrap As an undergraduate I found statistics a grind, obscured by a deluge of mathematical formulas and jargon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and Running With Fast.ai and Docker</title>
      <link>/2018/03/26/up-and-running-with-fast-ai-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/26/up-and-running-with-fast-ai-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday marked the start of the latest series of Fast.ai courses: Cutting Edge Deep Learning For Coders. If you have an interest in data science and haven’t heard of Fast.ai, you should check them out. Fast.ai is a community started by Jeremy Howard and Rachael Thomas in 2016. It now includes an impressive set of courses and a machine learning library by the same name. What sets them apart is their practical no nonsense approach to solving data science problems by example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>