<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Future Has Arrived</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Future Has Arrived</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction To The Boostrap For Quantitative Stock Selection</title>
      <link>/2018/05/30/an-introduction-to-the-boostrap-for-quantitative-stock-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/30/an-introduction-to-the-boostrap-for-quantitative-stock-selection/</guid>
      <description>Quantifying uncertainty is a fundamental and challenging task in financial modelling. In this post we’ll look at the bootstrap technique and how it can be applied to quantitative models. More generally, the bootstrap lies at the heart of a statistical technique know as Bootstap Aggregation (also known as bagging), which is the basis for machine learning algorithms such as random forest. We’ll look at Bagging in greater detail in the next post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and Running With Fast.ai and Docker</title>
      <link>/2018/03/26/up-and-running-with-fast-ai-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/26/up-and-running-with-fast-ai-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>Last Monday marked the start of the latest series of Fast.ai courses: Cutting Edge Deep Learning For Coders. If you have an interest in data science and haven’t heard of Fast.ai, you should check them out. Fast.ai is a community started by Jeremy Howard and Rachael Thomas in 2016. It now includes an impressive set of courses and a machine learning library by the same name. What sets them apart is their practical no nonsense approach to solving data science problems by example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>